var correct = 0;
var incorrect = 0;
var submitBtn = null;
var seconds = 90;
var intervalId = null;

// for (var i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {
// 	console.log(`The answer to ${questions[i].question} is ${questions[i].correctAnswer}`) }

var questions = [{
    question: "Which one of these characters did Angela not date?",
    answers: {
      a: "The Senator",
      b: "Dwight",
      c: "State Senator",
      d: "Andy"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "In season 5, who replaces Pam as the new receptionist?",
    answers: {
      a: "Kelly",
      b: "Erin",
      c: "Phyllis",
      d: "Creed"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "In season 7, episode 17 Michael finally debuts his action film to the office after ten years of writing, shooting, re-shooting and editing. What is the name of this film?",
    answers: {
      a: "Code Red Threat",
      b: "Threat Level Midnight",
      c: "Scarn vs. Goldenface",
      d: "Michael Bond"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "What is Creed Bratton's official job title?",
    answers: {
      a: "Salesman",
      b: "Accountant",
      c: "No one knows",
      d: "Quality Assurance Director"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "When did Jim buy Pam's engagement ring?",
    answers: {
      a: "While Pam was engaged to her first fiancÃ© Roy",
      b: "While Pam was away at Art School in New York City",
      c: "The first week that Jim and Pam started dating",
      d: "He never bought a ring"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "In season 5, when Michael Scott leaves Dunder Miflin, what is the name of his new paper company?",
    answers: {
      a: "The Dundees Paper Company",
      b: "Michael Scott Paper Company",
      c: "The Paper Connection",
      d: "PaperRUs"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "In season 1, episode 2 'Diversity Day', Michael imitates which famous comedians stand up routine?",
    answers: {
      a: "Richard Pryor",
      b: "Robin Williams",
      c: "Chris Rock",
      d: "George Carlin"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Which was NOT a prank that Jim successfully pulled on Dwight?",
    answers: {
      a: "Make Dwight to expect a mint at the sound of a computer log-in bell",
      b: "Jim impersonates Dwight by dressing up as a Dwight look-alike",
      c: 'Tricked Dwight into trading a $150 telescope for "miracle legumes" ',
      d: "Stealing beets from Dwight's bed-and-breakfast and beet farm"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: 'In S2E17 "Dwight\'s Speech": What infamous dictator\'s speech does Jim trick Dwight into giving at the sales conference?',
    answers: {
      a: "Adolf Hitler",
      b: "Kim Jong II",
      c: "Jospeh Stalin",
      d: "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the award show that Michael hosts every year?",
    answers: {
      a: "Michael's Awards",
      b: "The Dundies",
      c: "Dunder Mifflin Grammys",
      d: "The Dundie Show"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "In season 7, Toby is a jury member for what case?",
    answers: {
      a: "Scranton Strangler",
      b: "Dunder Mifflin Building Not Up To Code",
      c: "Ryan's Drug Problem",
      d: "Printers Set Fire"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
]

var getQuestions = function() {
  for (var i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {

    // creates a new div for each answer
    var newDiv = $(`<div id="format-questions">${questions[i].question}</div>`)
    var newRadioBtnA = $(`<div id="format-answers"><input type="radio" name="question-${i}-option" id="AnswerA" value="a"><label id="choiceA" for="AnswerA">${questions[i].answers.a}</label></div>`)
    var newRadioBtnB = $(`<div id="format-answers"><input type="radio" name="question-${i}-option" id="AnswerB" value="b"><label id="choiceB" for="AnswerB">${questions[i].answers.b}</label></div>`)
    var newRadioBtnC = $(`<div id="format-answers"><input type="radio" name="question-${i}-option" id="AnswerC" value="c"><label id="choiceC" for="AnswerC">${questions[i].answers.c}</label></div>`)
    var newRadioBtnD = $(`<div id="format-answers"><input type="radio" name="question-${i}-option" id="AnswerD" value="d"><label id="choiceD" for="AnswerD">${questions[i].answers.d}</label></div>`)

    // appends all radio buttons to the contentDiv
    $("#contentDiv").append(newDiv)
    $("#contentDiv").append(newRadioBtnA)
    $("#contentDiv").append(newRadioBtnB)
    $("#contentDiv").append(newRadioBtnC)
    $("#contentDiv").append(newRadioBtnD)


  }
}

// function passing into the setInterval function argument
var tick = function() {
  seconds--;
  $("#timeDiv").html(`<h2 class="time-format">Time Remaining: ${seconds} seconds</h2>`);
  if (seconds == 0) {
    clearInterval(intervalId);
    $("#timeDiv").hide()
    $("#contentDiv").hide()
    $("button").hide()
    $("#times-up").css("display", "initial")
    $("#times-up").html("<h1 class='no-time'>You've run out of time!</h2>")
    $("#times-up-reset").show()
    $("#times-up-reset").on("click", resetGame)


  }
}


var timer = function() {
  intervalId = setInterval(tick, 1000);
}
var submitBtn = null;
// on the start button click
$("#startBtn").on("click", function() {
  timer()
  $("#submit").css("display", "initial")
  $("#startBtn").hide();
  $("#start-btn-bg").hide()
  getQuestions()
  submitBtn = $("#submit").html("<button>submit</button>")
  $(".add-a-class-questions").removeClass("h-auto").addClass("height-class-questions")
  showResults()
})
// submit button appears after start to submit the results of the trivia
var showResults = function() {
  $(submitBtn).on("click", function() {
    getResults()
    console.log("working")
    $("#contentDiv").hide()
    $("#timeDiv").hide()
    $("#submit").hide()
    $("#resultsDiv").show();
    $("#resultsDiv").html()
    $("#reset-game").on("click", resetGame)
    $(".rightResults").html(correct);
    $(".wrongResults").html(incorrect);
    $(".add-a-class-results").removeClass("h-auto height-class-questions").addClass("height-class-results")
    clearInterval(intervalId);



  })
}
// reset game function - I can't figure out how to reset the questions so that none of the
// radio buttons are selected
var resetGame = function() {
  $("input").prop('checked', false);
  $("#timeDiv").empty()
  $("#resultsDiv").hide();
  $("#timeDiv").show()
  $("#contentDiv").show()
  $("#submit").show()
  $(".add-a-class-questions").removeClass("h-auto").addClass("height-class-questions")
  seconds = 90;
  clearInterval(intervalId);
  timer()


}


var userAnswer = null;
var getResults = function() {
  correct = 0;
  incorrect = 0;
  for (var i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {
    var currentQuestion = questions[i].correctAnswer;
    userAnswer = $(`input[name=question-${i}-option]:checked`).val()

    if (userAnswer === currentQuestion) {
      correct++;
      console.log(`correct count is ${correct}`);
      console.log("I think this is working right!");
    }
    // if one of the buttons in each question isn't checked alert must select something
    else {
      incorrect++
      console.log(`incorrect count is ${incorrect}`);

      console.log("wrong!");
    }
  }
}
var coolHover = function() {
  $("#startBtn").mouseover(function() {
    $("#start-btn-bg").css({
      "opacity": "1",
      "background": "#4484b9",
      "height": "50%"
    })
  })
}
var coolHoverTwo = function() {
  $("#startBtn").mouseout(function() {
    $("#start-btn-bg").css({
      "opacity": "0.9",
      "background": "#4484b9",
      "height": "50%"
    })
  })
}
// shows the time remaining as user scrolls - I'm really proud of this one lol
window.onscroll = function() {
  myFunction()
};

var header = document.getElementById("timeDiv");
var sticky = header.offsetTop;

function myFunction() {
  if (window.pageYOffset > sticky) {
    header.classList.add("sticky");
  } else {
    header.classList.remove("sticky");
  }
}


// runs the reset game function when the play again button is clicked
$("#reset-game").on("click", resetGame)
coolHover()
coolHoverTwo()
